Guide to the Alvin A. Achenbaum Papers, 1948-2011 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Alvin A. Achenbaum papers 1948-2011 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Achenbaum, Alvin A.
117.0 linear feet Extent: 80,000 Items
Market researcher and advertising executive who worked at several agencies; partner in a consulting practice under several names; lecturer and author of marketing textbooks. The Alvin A. Achenbaum Papers span the years 1948-2011 and document Achenbaum's career in advertising (with Grey Advertising, J. Walter Thompson and Backer Spielvogel Bates agencies) and marketing consulting (as a partner in Alvin Achenbaum Associates, Canter Achenbaum Heekin, and Achenbaum Bogda Associates). Collection includes writings and speeches, correspondence, photographs, research reports and related materials. Clients represented include 7-Eleven, American Red Cross, AT&T, Block Drug, Bristol-Myers, Campbell Soup, Chrysler, Dairy Queen, Dentsu, Franklin Mint, General Foods, GTE, Hallmark, Honda, Integrity Music, Kayser-Roth, Kia, K-Mart, Miller Brewing, MTA, Nationwide, Nestlé, Nissan/Datsun, PCA, Pfizer, Philip Morris, Quaker Oats, Revlon, Ryerson Tull, Seagram, Toyota, U.S. Dept. of Defense, and Warner-Lambert. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00010
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Research Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Alvin Achenbaum Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2012.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1944-1946 U.S. Army Air Corps
1950 B.S., Economics, UCLA
1951 M.S., Economics, Columbia University
1951-1957 McCann-Erickson Agency: Manager of Market Research; Economist and Market Analyst
1952-1957 Ph.D. candidate, Economics, Columbia University
1957-1971 Grey Advertising: Director of Marketing and Research; Vice President and Director of Marketing Services; Executive Vice President
1957-1971 Independent Research Company: interviewer and coder
1961-1964 Instructor, Bernard Baruch Graduate School of Public and Business Administration
1967 Instructor, Advanced Advertising Institute at New York University Graduate School of Business
1971-1974 J. Walter Thompson Company: Executive Vice President and Director of Marketing Services and Corporate Planning
1974-1989 Canter, Achenbaum, Associates: Chairman of the Board
1987-1996 M/A/R/C Group: Outside Member of the Board
1989-1992 Backer Spielvogel Bates: Vice Chairman; Member of the Board
1993-1995 Achenbaum Associates: President
1995-2004 Achenbaum Bogda Associates: Chairman of the Board
2005-present Achenbaum Institute of Marketing: President and Chief Executive Officer
Collection Overview
The Alvin A. Achenbaum Papers span the years 1948-2011 and document Achenbaum's career in advertising (with Grey Advertising, J. Walter Thompson and Backer Spielvogel Bates agencies) and marketing consulting (as a partner in Alvin Achenbaum Associates, Canter Achenbaum Heekin, and Achenbaum Bogda Associates). Collection includes writings and speeches, correspondence, photographs, research reports and related materials. Clients represented include 7-Eleven, American Red Cross, AT&T, Block Drug, Bristol-Myers, Campbell Soup, Chrysler, Dairy Queen, Dentsu, Franklin Mint, General Foods, GTE, Hallmark, Honda, Integrity Music, Kayser-Roth, Kia, K-Mart, Miller Brewing, MTA, Nationwide, Nestlé, Nissan/Datsun, PCA, Pfizer, Philip Morris, Quaker Oats, Revlon, Ryerson Tull, Seagram, Toyota, U.S. Dept. of Defense, and Warner-Lambert.
Collection Arrangement
Collection is organized into eleven series: General Files; Achenbaum Associates; Achenbaum Bogda Associates; Achenbaum Institute of Marketing; Achenbaum Marketing Communications; Backer Spielvogel Bates; Canter Achenbaum; Grey Advertising; J. Walter Thompson Company; Large Format Materials; and Writings and Speeches. Original folder titles have been maintained where possible.
Subject Headings
Achenbaum, Alvin A.; 7-Eleven, Inc.; American Honda Motor Company; American Red Cross; AT&T (Firm); Bates Worldwide, Inc.; Block Drug Company; Bristol-Myers Company; Campbell Soup Company; Chrysler Corporation; Dairy Queen (Firm); Dentsu; Distillers Corporation -- Seagrams Ltd; Franklin Mint; General Foods Corporation; General Telephone and Electronics Corporation; Grey Advertising, Inc.; Hallmark Cards, Inc.; Integrity Music, Inc.; J. Walter Thompson Company; Joseph T. Ryerson & Son; Kayser-Roth Corporation; Kia Motors; K-Mart Corporation; Metropolitan Transit Authority; Miller Brewing Company; Nationwide Mutual Insurance Company; Nestlé; Nissan Motor Corporation in U.S.A.; PCA International; Pfizer Inc.; Philip Morris and Company; Quaker Oats Company; Revlon, inc.; Toyota Jidosha Hanbai Kabushiki Kaisha; United States. Department of Defense; Warner-Lambert Company; Advertising; Advertising -- History; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- United States; Marketing; Marketing -- United States; Marketing consultants; Marketing consultants -- United States; Marketing research; Marketing research -- United States; Photographs; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Bates Worldwide, Inc. Records
D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles Archives
Irving Sonn Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company Advertising and Marketing Intelligence Database
J. Walter Thompson Company Anthony Viola Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company Corporation Vertical File
J. Walter Thompson Company Domestic Advertisements Collection
J. Walter Thompson Company Marketing Vertical File
J. Walter Thompson Company Nan Findlow Papers
Warwick Baker O'Neill Company Records
Wells Rich Greene Inc. Records
Wunderman Archives
Detailed Description of Collection
- General Files, 1949-2011 and undated
  - Documents
    - Achenbaum caricatures, undated (Box 1)
    - Advertising expenditures, 1990-1996 (Box 1)
    - Advertising for Democrats, 2006 (Box 1)
    - Agency compensation, 1975-1989, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - AMA conference, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Brand equity measurement, undated (Box 1)
    - Brand management, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Clinton campaign strategy, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Congressional communication proposal, 2004-2006 (Box 1)
    - Compensation data, 1980-2000, (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Creative advertising, 2008 (Box 2)
    - Curriculum vitae, 2005 and undated (Box 2)
    - Democratic campaigns, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Distance learning, 2005 (Box 2)
    - DVD production, undated (Box 2)
    - Environmental Solutions Worldwide, 2007-2009 (Box 2)
    - FTC presentations, 1967-1971 (Box 2)
    - Glamour Shots (Brightstar Studios), 1992-1993, (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - GSU Roundtable, 1991-1996 (Box 2)
    - Karlen Advertising, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Ken Bartlett correspondence, 2005 (Box 2)
    - Larry Killingsworth correspondence, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Letters regarding Advertising Age article, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
    - Lipton speech on branding (J. Stewart), 1986 (Box 3)
    - Marianne Gille-Lee correspondence, 2008 (Box 3)
    - Market forces, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Market structure and Nestlé, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
    - Market testing, 1981-1983 (Box 3)
    - Medical concept, 2003-2004 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous materials on market planning, 1957-1973 (Box 3)
    - NCTE talk on government and advertising, double speak, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Nestlé Management Communications Conference, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Nestlé Project Aurora, 1987 (Box 3)
    - New product development, undated (Box 3)
    - New product seminar, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Notes on a marketing newsletter, 1988 and undated (Box 3)
    - Notes on Russia trip (includes David Kidwell journal), 1992 (Box 3)
    - Oligopoly chart, undated (Box 4)
    - Other countries' educational programs, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Photographs, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - POPAI Marketplace, Chicago, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Popcorn Model correspondence, 2005 (Box 4)
    - Pricing, 1988-2004 (Box 4)
    - Questions and answers on job switch, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Requests for position papers, undated (Box 4)
    - Research data, 1989 (Box 4)
    - Russia trip, 1992 (Box 4)
    - Sales data on automobiles, 1975-1985 (Box 4)
    - Spielvogel/Democratic advertising, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Statements by heads of companies about brands, undated (Box 4)
    - Strategic Communication Program for Democrats to Regain Control of Both Houses of Congress in 2006, 2006, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Strategic Communication Program for Democrats to Regain Control of Both Houses of Congress in 2006, 2006, (2 of 2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Top-50 appliance store volume, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Total Marketing System, undated (Box 5)
    - Vittorini-Stanton correspondence, 1977 (Box 5)
    - Walmart Frame Company, 2005-2006 (Box 5)
    - Workshops
      - ANA Media Workshop, 1988 (Box 5)
      - Art and Craft of Marketing Sciences, 2006 (Box 5)
      - Branding, 1990 (Box 5)
      - Breakthrough Thinking and Implementation in Marketing Research, 2004 (Box 5)
      - Future of Marketing Research from a Historical Perspective, 2003 (Box 5)
      - How Can Marketing Research Adopt in the New Age to Benefit Top Management?, 2000 (Box 5)
      - How Can Marketing Research Do a Better Job of Predicting and Impacting the Future?, 1994 (Box 5)
      - How to Enhance Value of Marketing Research, 19969 (Box 5)
      - Increasing the Current and Future Role of Marketing Research, 2002 (Box 6)
      - Marketing Research, 2008 (Box 6)
      - Marketing Research and Corporate Profitability, 1993 (Box 6)
      - Marketing Research in the New Millennium, 1996 (Box 6)
      - Measuring Attitude Change/Product Testing, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous materials, 1998-2004 (Box 6)
      - New Approaches in Marketing Research, 1992 (Box 6)
      - Old, New, and New Again, 2007 (Box 6)
      - Opportunities in the New Millennium, 1999 (Box 6)
      - Revolutionary Research for a Revolutionary Age, 2001 (Box 6)
      - Surviving and Thriving in the New Economic Environment, 2009 (Box 6)
      - Your Part in an AMA Workshop Seminar, undated (Box 6)
    - Appointment Books, 1989-2011 (Box 7-8)
    - Contact files, undated (Box 9)
  - Printed Materials
    - AAAA--The Value Side of Productivity, 1990 (Box 10)
    - A Proposed New Research Program for Campbell's Soup, 1977 (Box 10)
    - Achenbaum press, 1975-1992 (Box 10)
    - Acura Style, 2004 Summer (Box 10)
    - Ad Day USA, 1975-1977, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Advertiser, 1995, 2000 (Box 10)
    - Advertising Age, 1988 Feb. 15 (Box 10)
    - Advertising Age Creative Workshop brochure, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Advertising agency compensation articles, 1986-1993 (Box 10)
    - Advertising Agency Compensation: Princip-le Versus Princip-al, 1989 (Box 10)
    - Advertising Agency Reputations, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Advertising Agency Searches (Sandy Sulcer), 1998 (Box 10)
    - Advertising budget articles, 1963-1973 (Box 10)
    - Advertising diversification, 1988 (Box 10)
    - Advertising expenditures, 2003 (Box 10)
    - Advertising frequency research, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Advertising, general theory, 1982-1988 (Box 11)
    - Advertising, global, 1986-1988 (Box 11)
    - Advertising in the United States, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Advertising industry, general, 1988-1989 (Box 11)
    - Advertising Research at Benton & Bowles, undated (Box 11)
    - Advertising Research Foundation, 1984, 2004 (Box 11)
    - Advertising research papers, 1973-1974 (Box 11)
    - Advertising Sales Promotion and the Bottom Line (Ogilvy & Mather), 1989 (Box 11)
    - Adweek, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Adweek Marketing Week, 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Adweek Superbrands, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - Agency, 1999-2001, (3 folders) (Box 11)
    - Agency Compensation A New Approach, 1974 (Box 11)
    - Agency family trees, 2006 (Box 12)
    - Agency of the Future, undated (Box 12)
    - Agency performance papers, 1976-1980 (Box 12)
    - AIM Brands (feature on Heinz), 1991 (Box 12)
    - American Marketing Association, undated (Box 12)
    - ANA speech, 1989 (Box 12)
    - ANA survey on compensation, 1975 (Box 12)
    - ANNY, 1963, 1977 (Box 12)
    - Articles about Achenbaum, 1966-1999, (1-4 of 5 folders) (Box 12)
    - Articles about Achenbaum, 1966-1999, (5 of 5 folders) (Box 13)
    - Articles about agencies, 2000-2002 (Box 13)
    - Articles about public transportation, 1971-1989 (Box 13)
    - Articles on agency selection, 1966-1973 (Box 13)
    - Articles on brand equity/brand extension, 1978-1991 (Box 13)
    - Articles on media, 1988-2007 (Box 13)
    - Articles on test marketing, 1962-1970 (Box 13)
    - Attitude valuation studies, 1958-1966 (Box 13)
    - Audits and surveys, 1974 (Box 14)
    - Bloomingdale's, 2003 (Box 14)
    - Brand management, 1993 (Box 14)
    - Branding, 1970-2004 (Box 14)
    - Bruce Bendinger articles, 1988-2008 (Box 14)
    - Causes, 1984-1988 (Box 14)
    - CBA Reporter, 1991 Summer (Box 14)
    - Challenging the Definition of Innovation for Consumer Packaged Goods, circa 2005 (Box 14)
    - Clients and media, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Clinton articles, 2005-2006 (Box 14)
    - Clinton campaign, 1989 and undated (Box 14)
    - Comedy Central articles, 1993 (Box 14)
    - Camiday Familia, 2004 (Box 14)
    - Compete through Service, 2008 (Box 14)
    - Continuous Information Systems, 1971 (Box 14)
    - Creative media, 2000 (Box 14)
    - Creative Research (Niki Kominik et al), 1965 (Box 14)
    - Credits, direct marketing issue, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Current articles on marketing, 2005 (Box 14)
    - Data, 1987-1988 (Box 15)
    - Datsun/Nissan clippings, 1977 (Box 15)
    - Decision Support Systems for Marketing, 1989 (Box 15)
    - Defining Advertising Potentials (Look Magazine), 1962 (Box 15)
    - Delaney Report, 2004 (Box 15)
    - Destiny of Direct (Howard Draft), 1992 (Box 15)
    - Digital industry, 1994-1995 (Box 15)
    - Dr. Dean presentation, 2006 (Box 15)
    - Economic Growth in the Seventies, 1970 (Box 15)
    - Economic Indications, 2003-2009, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Economist, 2004 Nov. 20 (Box 15)
    - Education at a Glance (OECD), 2007 (Box 15)
    - Education Counts (UNESCO), 2007 (Box 15)
    - Effective Frequency (ARF), 1982 (Box 15)
    - Effective Promotion Strategies (Ambar Rao and Arthur Stern), 1978 (Box 16)
    - Ephron on Media, 2006 (Box 16)
    - European Lifestyle (Mintel), 1989 (Box 16)
    - Explanation of the ANA/AAAA Presentation on Advertising to the FTC, 1971 (Box 16)
    - Flops (Christopher Power), 1993 (Box 16)
    - Food sales data, 1975-1989 (Box 16)
    - Forget the Product Life Cycle Concept (Nariman Dhalla and Sonia Yuspeh), 1976 (Box 16)
    - Frozen Food (Mintel), 1989 (Box 16)
    - FTC testimony, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Future Brand, undated (Box 16)
    - Future of Retailing (Leo Bogart), 1973 (Box 16)
    - Gallup Store Brands vs. National Brands, undated (Box 16)
    - Getting Real about Spending Trends for U.S. Advertising and Marketing, 1989 (Box 16)
    - Global Education Digest, 2007 (Box 16)
    - Guide for Handbook Contributors, 1964 (Box 17)
    - Guide to Cable Programming, 1996-1997 (Box 17)
    - Hallmark loyalty promotion, 1999 (Box 17)
    - Harper's, 2004 Dec. (Box 17)
    - Hispanic Fact Pack, 2004 (Box 17)
    - History of direct advertising (Internet downloads), 2010 (Box 17)
    - How Advertising Works (Foote Cone Belding), 1979 (Box 17)
    - How Much Advertising is Enough? (Foote Cone Belding), undated (Box 17)
    - How to Create Advertising that Sells (Ogilvy & Mather), undated (Box 17)
    - How to Get More Business than You Thought Possible, 2001 (Box 17)
    - How to Introduce New Market Entries (Booz-Allen and Hamilton), 1973 (Box 17)
    - How to Involve Procurement in Managing the Advertising Budget (Alan Krinsky), 2004 (Box 17)
    - How to Organize for New Products (Samuel Johnson and Conrad Jones), 1957 (Box 17)
    - How Word-of-Mouth Advertising Works (Ernest Dichter), 1966 (Box 17)
    - In Defense of Price Promotion (Paul Ferris and John Quelch), 1987 (Box 17)
    - Incite Management, 2006 (Box 17)
    - Innovation in Retailing, 2005 (Box 17)
    - Interactive television advertising scenarios, undated (Box 17)
    - Internet definitions, undated (Box 17)
    - Is the Party Over? (Christy Marshall), 1987 (Box 17)
    - It's a Broadband Life (Yahoo!), circa 2004 (Box 17)
    - Jon Achenbaum feature, 1992 (Box 17)
    - Journal of Advertising Research, 1973, 1988, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - Journal of Marketing, Early Prediction of Market Success for New Grocery Products (Louis Fourt and Joseph Woodlock), 1960 (Box 17)
    - J. Walter Thompson--Flippers, 1987 (Box 17)
    - KEA Development News, 1983 (Box 17)
    - Keith Roberts, History of Business, undated (Box 17)
    - Kraft Food and Family, 2003 (Box 17)
    - Kraft Kitchens calendar, 2004 (Box 17)
    - K-Mart search articles, 1995 (Box 17)
    - Leveraging to Beat the Odds, the New Marketing Mindset (Adrian Slywotzky and Benson Shapiro), 1993 (Box 18)
    - Longevity of Accounts in the Advertising Agency Business (AAAA), 1997 (Box 18)
    - Magazine Publishers Association seminar series, 1977 (Box 18)
    - Management of New Products (Booz-Allen and Hamilton), undated (Box 18)
    - Managing brand equity, 1991 and undated (Box 18)
    - Manhattan, Inc., 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Market Intelligence (Mintel), 1983 (Box 18)
    - Marketing Audit Comes of Age (Philip Kotler et al), 1977 (Box 18)
    - Marketing books, 2005 (Box 18)
    - Marketing Fact Book, 2003 (Box 18)
    - Marketing--General, 1982-1988 (Box 18)
    - Marketing Leadership Council--Research Archives, 2003 Jan. (Box 18)
    - Marketing Management, 2000-2004, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Marketing News, 1976-2004, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Marketing Research Program membership list, 1973 (Box 18)
    - Mass Media Research (William Belson, Market Research Society of Australia), 1961 (Box 18)
    - Measuring Payout (ARF), 1973 (Box 18)
    - Measuring Preference for Product Benefits Across Countries (Steve Cohen, Leopoldo Neira), 2004 (Box 18)
    - Media Decisions, 1973 (Box 19)
    - Media frequency articles, 1983-1988 (Box 19)
    - Media/Scope, 1966-1968, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous agency advertisements, undated (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1952-2006, (4 folders) (Box 19)
    - Multi-Market Testing (Valentine Appel, B&B), 1964 (Box 19)
    - New market entry course, 1972-1973 (Box 19)
    - New product branding articles, 1972 and undated (Box 19)
    - New Product Distribution (David Montgomery), 1973 (Box 19)
    - New Profession to Aid Management (Marion Harper Jr.), 1960 (Box 19)
    - Newsweek, e-Live feature, 1999 (Box 20)
    - New York Chapter (AMA) Newsletter, 1964 Jan. (Box 20)
    - Nielsen Researcher, 1972, 1980 (Box 20)
    - On the Horizon (Hispanic market), 2004 (Box 20)
    - Online Nation (I. Elaine Allen, Jeff Seaman), 2007 (Box 20)
    - Other Advertising, 2005 May (Box 20)
    - Overview of Sources to Support Growth of Riverside (Kima Consulting), 2004 (Box 20)
    - Papers by A.S.C. Ehrenberg, 1963-1964 (Box 20)
    - PepsiCo, The Power of Brands, 1990 (Box 20)
    - PIMS: A Breakthrough in Strategic Planning, 1973 (Box 20)
    - Plan: University courses, 2005-2006 (Box 20)
    - Point of Purchase (Bob Stark), 1973 (Box 20)
    - Political clippings, 2003 and undated (Box 20)
    - Political materials, 2001-2003 (Box 20)
    - Power: Horizontal integration, 1988 and undated (Box 20)
    - Power: Vertical integration, 1986-1988 and undated (Box 20)
    - Presentation on Advertising Expenditures (Robert Coen), 2004 (Box 20)
    - Presidential election, 1988 (Box 20)
    - Pricing from the Seller's Standpoint (Joel Dean), 1949 (Box 20)
    - Printers' Ink, 1963-1965, (4 folders) (Box 21)
    - Procedure for Estimating Survey Research Volume, undated (Box 21)
    - Product development report (Ogilvy & Mather), undated (Box 21)
    - Product Research Methodology (Market Facts), 1957 (Box 21)
    - Profits, negotiated fees, 2007-2010, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Project Group Inc. (PGI)--Point of View on Agency Compensation, undated (Box 21)
    - Promotion Development Process (Einson Freeman), undated (Box 21)
    - Promotion research, 1981-1984 (Box 21)
    - Promotion research--Coupons, 1981-1983 (Box 21)
    - Promotional Panache (Eugene Mahany, Needham Harper & Steers), 1976 (Box 21)
    - Radio advertising, retail groups, 2004 (Box 21)
    - Related Recall Norms for Day-After-Recall Tests (Burke), 1982 (Box 22)
    - Reviewer's View (Noreen O'Leary), 1992 (Box 22)
    - Richard Morcoan, Adweek, 1992 (Box 22)
    - Robert White letters to editor, Adweek, 1986 (Box 22)
    - Role of the Sales Promotion Agency in Marketing (CSPA), 1974 (Box 22)
    - Sales Estimates for New Market Plans (Satterthwaite Research), 1963 (Box 22)
    - Sales Management, 1963-1966, (2 folders) (Box 22)
    - Science and Truth in Marketing Research (Alfred Politz), 1957 (Box 22)
    - Scientific American, 1963 Apr. (Box 22)
    - Selling off the Back Panel (Nestlé), 1988 (Box 22)
    - SM Trend Report: In the Land of the Blind, 1965 (Box 22)
    - Social Change Briefs, 2000 (Box 22)
    - Story of the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, draft, undated (Box 22)
    - Street Smarts (memoir by Joel Baumwoll), 2001 (Box 22)
    - Summary of Comsat proposals, undated (Box 22)
    - Superpremium Premium (Leslie Moeller et al), 2004 (Box 22)
    - Television: Things Will Never Be the Same (Ogilvy & Mather), 1988 (Box 22)
    - Television advertising articles, 1987-2006 (Box 22)
    - Test Marketing, undated (Box 23)
    - Time, Get Rich.com feature, 1999 (Box 23)
    - Top of Mind, Decline of Brands (Jack Gordon), 2004 (Box 23)
    - Trademarks and the Arts (William Borchard), 1999 (Box 23)
    - Velocity, 2002 (Box 23)
    - Ventures, Building a Brand, 2005 (Box 23)
    - Viewpoint (Ogilvy & Mather), 1987 (Box 23)
    - Washington City Paper (Jonathan Agronsky article), 2001 (Box 23)
    - What America Eats (Parade), 1991 (Box 23)
    - What Ogilvy & Mather Has Learned About How Much to Spend on Advertising, undated (Box 23)
    - What Ogilvy & Mather Has Learned About Introducing New Products, undated, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - What Ogilvy & Mather Has Learned About Sales Promotion, undated (Box 23)
    - What Search Consultants Think Agencies Should Know (Sandy Sulcer), 1998 (Box 23)
    - Wheel of Marketing (J.O. Peckham), 1967 (Box 23)
    - Who Holds the Answer to the Health of Your Brand? (M/A/R/C), undated (Box 23)
    - Who Pays for the Media? (Leo Burnett), 1994 (Box 23)
    - Will Negroes Back Christmas Boycott?, 1963 (Box 23)
    - Young & Rubicam Brand Asset Valuator, 1995 (Box 23)
    - Focus group cards, undated (Box 24)
  - Audiovisual Materials
    - Achenbaum Bogda Template. Powerpoint presentation on CD-R. 2003. (Box 25)
    - Beer Market Structure. Powerpoint presentation on CD-R. Undated. (Box 25)
    - Franklin Mint. Tape of Princess Diana. VHS. Undated. (Box 25)